Mss.Ms.Coll.23
American Philosophical Society
Harrison Dailey Stalker papers, 1936-1977
Mss.Ms.Coll.23
American Philosophical Society
2.0 Linear feet
2 linear feet.
This collection of correspondence, reports, and manuscripts concerns Stalker's research in genetics and evolutionary biology, particularly the evolutionary genetics of Drosophila. Most of the letters are scientific, although the usual academic politics in various departments is mentioned. There is also material on the Society for the Study of Evolution (1970).
Stalker, Harrison D. (Harrison Dailey), 1915-1982
Box 1-4
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Mrs. H. D. Stalker and accessioned, 06/22/1983 (1983 826ms).
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, reports, manuscripts, research data. Letters deal with scientific matters, academic politics, and the affairs of the Society for the Study of Evolution.
Biographical/Historical note
Harrison Dailey Stalker was a geneticist and zoologist.
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Carson, Hampton L. Correspondence (2 folders) 1951-1975
Dobzhansky, Theodosius Correspondence (8 items) 1938-1969
Glass, Bentley Correspondence (4 items) 1948-1953
Levitan, Max Correspondence (3 folders) 1947-1972
Lewontin, Richard Charles Correspondence (6 items) 1965-1969
Mayr, Ernst Correspondence (5 items) 1946-1948
Miller, Dwight D. Correspondence (3 folders) 1941-1970
Muller, Hermann Joseph Correspondence (2 items) 1966
Patterson, John Thomas Correspondence (18 items) 1940-1946
Reed, Sheldon Clark Correspondence (1 item) 1946
Society for the Study of Evolution Records (4 folders) 1970
Spencer, Warren P. Correspondence (3 folders) 1935-1975
Stern, Curt Correspondence (8 items) 1940-1970
Sturtevant, Alfred Henry Correspondence (2 folders) 1938-1962
Carson,, Hampton L. (Hampton Lawrence), 1914-; Dobzhansky, Theodosius Grigorievich, 1900-1975; Glass, Bentley, 1906-2005; Levitan, Max; Lewontin, Richard Charles, 1929-; Mayr, Ernst, 1904-2005; Miller, Dwight Dana, 1914-; Muller, H. J., (Hermann Joseph), 1890-1967; Reed, Sheldon Clark, 1910-; Society for the Study of Evolution.; Spencer, Warren P.; Sturtevant, A. H. (Alfred Henry), 1891-; Biology.; Drosophila.; Evolution.; Genetics.; Manuscripts (for publication).; Reports.
- Selected Inventory from Genetics Subject Guide
  - Carson, Hampton L., 1951-1975; Correspondence ( 2 folders )
    Conferences and symposia; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila genetics -- Nomenclature; Genetics of plants; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication -- Genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Committee activities; Travel -- Australia; Travel -- Hawaii; Travel -- Japan; University of Hawaii; University of Melbourne; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Washington University (Saint Louis, Mo.); Zoology
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1938-1969; Correspondence ( 8 items )
    Drosophila genetics; Graduate study; National Institutes of Health; Publication; Stern, Curt; Sturtevant, Alfred Henry; Travel -- Mexico
  - Glass, Bentley, 1948-1953; Correspondence ( 4 items )
    Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters -- Quarterly Review of Biology; Reviews
  - Levitan, Max, 1947-1972; Correspondence ( 3 folders )
    Botany and plant genetics; Carson, Hampton L.; Dobzhansky, Theodosius; Drosophila genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Population genetics; Publication -- Evolution; Teaching; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Wallace, Bruce
  - Lewontin, Richard Charles, 1965-1969; Correspondence ( 6 items )
    American Society of Naturalists -- Committee activities; Recommendations; Referee's report -- American Naturalist
  - Mayr, Ernst, 1946-1948; Correspondence ( 5 items )
    Carson, Hampton L.; Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters; Publication -- Evolution
  - Miller, Dwight D., 1941-1970; Correspondence ( 3 folders )
    Biographical and personal data; California Institute of Technology; Carson, Hampton L.; Conferences and symposia; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Research support; Sturtevant, Alfred Henry; Travel -- Canada; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Muller, Hermann Joseph, 1966; Correspondence ( 2 items )
    Evolution; Lectures, public speaking; Political issues
  - Patterson, John Thomas, 1940-1946; Correspondence ( 18 items )
    Conferences and symposia; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Stone, Wilson Stuart; University of Texas
  - Reed, Sheldon Clark, 1946; Correspondence ( 1 item )
    Drosophila genetics; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Society for the Study of Evolution, 1970; Records ( 4 folders )
    American Association for the Advancement of Science; American Institute of Biological Sciences; Business; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Educational matters; Evolution; Lewontin, Richard Charles; National Science Foundation; Political issues; Publication -- Evolution; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Spencer, Warren P., 1935-1975; Correspondence ( 3 folders )
    Biographical and personal data; Drosophila genetics; Fellowships, assistantships; Graduate study; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; Neel, James V.; Patterson, John Thomas; Publication; Publication -- Genetics; Recommendations; Stern, Curt; Sturtevant, Alfred Henry; Teaching; University of Rochester; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Stern, Curt, 1940-1970; Correspondence ( 8 items )
    Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Drosophila genetics; Hadorn, Ernst; Human genetics; Photographs; Spencer, Warren P.; Teaching; University of Rochester
  - Sturtevant, Alfred Henry, 1938-1962; Correspondence ( 2 folders )
    Drosophila genetics; Fellowships, assistantships--California Institute of Technology; Research support; Spencer, Warren P.; Stern, Curt